Jane Hoffswell

Email: jhoffs@cs.washington.edu Website: https://homes.cs.washington.edu/~jhoffs

RESEARCH STATEMENT

My research aims to help end user programmers more effectively author, understand, and reuse code and data through the design of new languages and program visualization tools. New declarative programming languages can raise the level of abstraction to focus on relevant domain-specific details. Improved tools can better align with and enrich end user programmers' mental models. Visualizing program state and behavior promotes program understanding, and can proactively surface surprising or incorrect results.

EDUCATION

PHD CANDIDATE COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING
MS COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING, June 2016
Paul G. Allen School of Computer Science & Engineering
University of Washington (UW), Seattle, WA
Advisor: Jeffrey Heer
September 2014 - Present

BS COMPUTER SCIENCE

Harvey Mudd College (HMC), Claremont, CA

Advisor: Ben Wiedermann August 2010 - May 2014

PUBLICATIONS

Interactive Repair of Tables Extracted from PDF Documents on Mobile Devices.

Jane Hoffswell and Zhicheng Liu.

ACM Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI), 2019. https://doi.org/10.1145/3290605.3300523

SetCoLa: High-Level Constraints for Graph Layout.

Jane Hoffswell, Alan Borning, Jeffrey Heer.

Computer Graphics Forum (Proc. Euro Vis), 2018. https://doi.org/10.1111/cgf.13440

Augmenting Code with In Situ Visualizations to Aid Program Understanding.

Jane Hoffswell, Arvind Satyanarayan, Jeffrey Heer.

ACM Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI), 2018. https://doi.org/10.1145/3173574.3174106

Supporting Patient-Provider Collaboration to Identify Individual Triggers using Food and Symptom Journals. Jessica Schroeder, **Jane Hoffswell**, Chia-Fang Chung, James Fogarty, Sean Munson, Jasmine Zia. *ACM Computer-Supported Cooperative Work (CSCW)*, 2017. https://doi.org/10.1145/2998181.2998276

Visual Debugging Techniques for Reactive Data Visualization.

Jane Hoffswell, Arvind Satyanarayan, Jeffrey Heer.

Computer Graphics Forum (Proc. EuroVis), 2016. https://doi.org/10.1111/cgf.12903

Reactive Vega: A Streaming Dataflow Architecture for Declarative Interactive Visualization.

Arvind Satyanarayan, Ryan Russell, Jane Hoffswell, Jeffrey Heer.

IEEE Trans. Visualization & Comp. Graphics (Proc. InfoVis), 2016. https://doi.org/10.1109/TVCG.2015.2467091

HONOS AND AWARDS

2014	Jeff Dean - Heidi Hopper Endowed Regental Fellowship Recipient
2014	Harvey Mudd College Computer Science Clinic Poster Award
2014	Honorable Mention CRA Undergraduate Research Award Competition
2011-2014	Harvey Mudd College Dean's List
2010	International Baccalaureate

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Summer 2019 Seattle, WA	RESEARCH INTERN, ADOBE RESEARCH Advisors: Leo Zhicheng Liu and Wilmot Li.
Summer 2018 Seattle, WA	RESEARCH INTERN, ADOBE RESEARCH Interactive Repair of Tables Extracted from PDF Documents on Mobile Devices Advisor: Leo Zhicheng Liu. Conducted research on the future of dynamic PDF documents and the analysis and reuse of PDF tables for dynamic use cases on mobile devices.
2013-2014 Claremont, CA	PROJECT MANAGER, CAPSTONE PROJECT, HMC COMPUTER SCIENCE DEPARTMENT Visualizing and Exploring Performance Data alongside VMware Advisor: Melissa O'Neill. Project Manager for a senior capstone project with VMware. Developed a dashboard for visualizing system performance using D3.js.
Summer 2013 Claremont, CA	Undergraduate Research Assistant, HMC Computer Science Department Visualizing the Graphical Execution of Abstract Program Traces Advisor: Ben Wiedermann. Modified the UC Santa Barbara JavaScript Abstract Interpreter to output information about the abstract program trace and implemented a tool for visualizing program traces using D3.js.
Summer 2012 Claremont, CA	Undergraduate Research Assistant, HMC Computer Science Department Large Scale, Educational Video Games for Middle School Students Advisor: Elizabeth Sweedyk. Developed a math-based game for the iPad that teaches children about ratios by taking advantage of the ratio-based behavior of mixing paint.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

2016-2017 Seattle, WA	TEACHING ASSISTANT, UW PAUL. G. ALLEN SCHOOL OF COMPUTER SCIENCE & ENGINEERING Professor: Jeffrey Heer. Graded coursework, held office hours, and led tutorial sessions for the graduate (Spring 2016) and undergraduate (Spring 2017) Data Visualization courses.
Winter 2014 Seattle, WA	TEACHING ASSISTANT, UW MASTERS IN HUMAN COMPUTER INTERACTION + DESIGN Professor: Jeffrey Heer. Helped to develop the course curriculum. Tutored and graded coursework for students studying User Interface Software & Technology (Winter 2014).
2012-2014 Claremont, CA	TUTOR AND GRADER, HMC COMPUTER SCIENCE DEPARTMENT Tutored and graded classes on Programming Languages (Spring 2014), Artificial Intelligence (Spring 2014), Software Development (Spring 2013, Fall 2013), and the Principles of Computer Science (Fall 2012).

WORKSHOPS AND PRESENTATIONS

Spring 2019 Languages & Visualizations to Enable Effective End User Programming.

GLASGOW, UK Jane Hoffswell. ACM Human Factors in Computing Systems Extended Abstracts (CHI EA),

2019. https://doi.org/10.1145/3290607.3299067

Spring 2015 Debugging Vega through Inspection of the Data Flow Graph.

Cagliari, Italy Jane Hoffswell, Arvind Satyanarayan, Jeffrey Heer. Euro Vis Workshop on Reproducibility,

Verification, and Validation in Visualization (EuroRV3), 2015.

https://doi.org/10.2312/eurorv3.20151144

Spring 2014 VISUALIZING THE GRAPHICAL EXECUTION OF ABSTRACT PROGRAM TRACES.

San Diego, CA Southern California Celebration for Women in Computing.

Fall 2013 VISUALIZING THE GRAPHICAL EXECUTION OF ABSTRACT PROGRAM TRACES.

Los Angeles, CA Southern California Programming Languages and Systems Workshop.

POSTERS

Spring 2019 Languages & Visualizations to Enable Effective End User Programming.

GLASGOW, UK ACM Human Factors in Computing Systems Doctoral Consortium Poster, 2019.

Fall 2016 Visual Debugging Techniques for Reactive Data Visualization.

SEATTLE, WA University of Washington Computer Science & Engineering Affiliates, 2016.

LEADERSHIP AND VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

2017-Present REVIEWER for IEEE Visualization Conference (VIS 2019, VIS 2018), ACM Symposium on

User Interface Software and Technology (UIST 2019, UIST 2018, UIST 2017),

ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI 2019, CHI 2017),

and Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics (TVCG 2018).

Winter 2018 HCI VISIT DAYS COORDINATOR, UW COMPUTER SCIENCE & ENGINEERING

SEATTLE, WA Organized group activities and one-on-one meetings for admitted graduate students.

Fall 2016 GRADUATE STUDENT ADMISSIONS VOLUNTEER, UW COMPUTER SCIENCE & ENGINEERING

SEATTLE, WA Reviewed graduate student admissions applications.

Fall 2015 New Graduate Orientation Leader, UW Computer Science & Engineering

Seattle, WA Coordinated talks from current students and faculty for incoming PhD students.

Organized activities and lead the two-day orientation.

Fall 2015 PROJECT MANAGER, USLI ROCKETRY TEAM, HARVEY MUDD COLLEGE

SEATTLE, WA Founder and project manager of a NASA sponsored University Student Launch Initiative

(USLI) rocketry team that designed and launched a rocket with a scientific payload.